<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal notes</title>
    <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Personal notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 Simon Fels | Made with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mojoaar/hucore.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hucore theme&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; ♥ | &lt;a href=&#34;https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/dsgvo/index.html&#34;&gt;Data policy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/impressum/index.html&#34;&gt;Imprint&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the Anbox journey to the next level</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2020-01-21-taking-the-anbox-journey-to-the-next-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2020-01-21-taking-the-anbox-journey-to-the-next-level/</guid>
      <description>Today, Canonical released Anbox Cloud which builds upon the same ideas as I built Anbox on in 2017. I am thankful that Canonical allowed me to take the idea of Anbox to the next level, form an engineering team around it and bring it as a fully supported product to any cloud (private or public, thanks to the magic of Juju) for a wide variety of use cases. It covers more advanced use cases like cloud gaming or application streaming for enterprises down to providing an on-premise Android cluster for development and testing of Android applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datenschutzerklärung</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/dsgvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/dsgvo/</guid>
      <description>Diese Datenschutzerklärung klärt Sie über die Art, den Umfang und Zweck der Verarbeitung von personenbezogenen Daten (nachfolgend kurz „Daten“) innerhalb unseres Onlineangebotes und der mit ihm verbundenen Webseiten, Funktionen und Inhalte sowie externen Onlinepräsenzen, wie z.B. unser Social Media Profile auf (nachfolgend gemeinsam bezeichnet als „Onlineangebot“). Im Hinblick auf die verwendeten Begrifflichkeiten, wie z.B. „Verarbeitung“ oder „Verantwortlicher“ verweisen wir auf die Definitionen im Art. 4 der Datenschutzgrundverordnung (DSGVO).
Verantwortlicher Simon FelsAchtern Hoff 28a27283 VerdenDeutschlandE-Mail: morphis [at] gravedo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anbox - Android in a Box</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2017-04-10-introducing-anbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2017-04-10-introducing-anbox/</guid>
      <description>Today I am making a private side-project public I am working on for more than 1.5 years now. Back in 2015 I started working on a prototype of what I call Anbox today. It was born out of the idea of putting Android into a simple container based on LXC and bridging relevant parts over to the host operating system while not allowing any access to real hardware or user data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG:
Simon FelsAchtern Hoff 28a27283 VerdenKontakt:E-Mail: morphis [at] gravedo.deHaftung für Inhalte Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.
Verpflichtungen zur Entfernung oder Sperrung der Nutzung von Informationen nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen bleiben hiervon unberührt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Communication in Smart Grids</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2013-06-19-secure-communication-in-smart-grids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 09:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2013-06-19-secure-communication-in-smart-grids/</guid>
      <description>Due to the last weeks and months I worked on a university project about secure communications within smart grids. As one of its results we published a paper summarizing our efforts of creating a secure communication infrastructure for it which is based on trusted computing. The paper is submitted at the german DACH Security 2013 conference.
The whole paper is in german an can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Debian packages</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2012-05-09-building-debian-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 12:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2012-05-09-building-debian-packages/</guid>
      <description>As we released a new version of the Freesmarpthone.org middleware some time ago I am very interested in getting this into the Debian distribution and finally Ubuntu. As the various components are already available in Debian the initial packaging work is almost done and just needs to be updated to ship the recent version. As this is the first time for me with packaging something for Debian I want to share my steps to setup the packging repository here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade from Debian Lenny to Squeeze</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2012-05-04-upgrade-from-debian-lenny-to-squeeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2012-05-04-upgrade-from-debian-lenny-to-squeeze/</guid>
      <description>Today I upgrade my server finally from Debian lenny to squeeze (which was released already last year, but I never had the time to do the upgrade since today). All in all the upgrade process went very fine. Following the release upgrade notes helped a lot and saved me some time (see 0).
Finally I migrated to a dependency based boot system too. I already started with this last year but stopped it a second time cause of missing time for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World is small …</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-08-11-world-is-small/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 20:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-08-11-world-is-small/</guid>
      <description>After a long time I got finally supported by HP (you know they bought Palm and webOS back in 2010) with a HP Veer device for development. Back in feburary 2011 HP started a Free Pre 2 Device program and I wrote to them to get qualified for a device. After more than 8 months I finally got a device (not the Pre 2 but who cares). The HP Veer is a very tiny device I like very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One to rule them all!</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-06-28-one-to-rule-them-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 15:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-06-28-one-to-rule-them-all/</guid>
      <description>Talking about modem processors used in todays smartphones is a sad story. Most of them are using a binary protocol which is not known by the public. In some cases the linux userland is talking plain AT over a serial line with the modem but that&#39;s expected. Let me list some devices:
 Palm Pre/Pre Pus/Pre 2: All three have a MSM6280 modem chip and are using a binary protocol for modem access from the application processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS capabilities of the HP Veer smartphone</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-05-16-foss-capabilities-of-the-hp-veer-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 07:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-05-16-foss-capabilities-of-the-hp-veer-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday HP released their new smartphone the HP Veer in the US to the market. At the same they released their webOS doctor for the new phone which is the ulitity you use when your device gets broken some way. It contains the whole rootfs and kernel files for the device so I was able to do some first research about the FOSS capabilities of the new device. Here are my first notes about the device and the software it&#39;s using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Pre Plus Smartphone from Palm</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-01-12-free-pre-plus-smartphone-from-palm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 07:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2011-01-12-free-pre-plus-smartphone-from-palm/</guid>
      <description>Yeah! I finally got my free Pre Plus smartphone from Palm! In late September I wrote to Palm as they offered free Pre Plus devices for qualified developers:
Hello, as I read in our newsletter you are offering free Pre Plus devices to qualified developers. I am one of the people trying to bring an open and free operating system to the great Palm Pre device. We are comming originally from the Openmoko project and searching for a new device which can be the base for our further development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSO Palm Pre Modem Status Report</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2010-06-09-fso-palm-pre-modem-status-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 08:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2010-06-09-fso-palm-pre-modem-status-report/</guid>
      <description>Through my last three weeks on holiday I got a lot things implemented in msmcomm. We now have the following working:
 call support: dial, answer and end calls (only call forwarding and call conference stuff is missing) various network information: network-list, rssi, current nework, network time, mode preference (GSM/UMTS/auto) various system related things: set system time, modem audio tuning parameters, audio profiles, charging SIM: read/write/delete phonebooks, verify pin, enable/disable pin, change pin, sim info (imsi, misdn), phonebook properties  This is already a lot we can work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSO on the Palm Pre – Short Status Update</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2010-04-23-fso-on-the-palm-pre-short-status-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 08:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2010-04-23-fso-on-the-palm-pre-short-status-update/</guid>
      <description>For a long time we&#39;re now hacking on the Palm Pre device to get FSO working: Time for a short summary were we are and what has do be done in the near future (mickey already pointed out which components are working and which not).
Modem
The modem was the big show stopper when we initial began with hacking on the Palm Pre. The protocol Palm uses to communicate with the modem is nothing already known in the FOSS community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSO Palm Pre Code-Sprint</title>
      <link>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2010-03-03-fso-palm-pre-code-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 10:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mm.gravedo.de/blog/posts/2010-03-03-fso-palm-pre-code-sprint/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow I will meet with Mickey to work with him on FSO support for the Palm Pre. In the last month I worked mostly on the implementation of the protocol between userland and modem in the Palm Pre and we are now able to react on incomming calls and only one step away from doing our own calls.
Most part of our work tomorrow will be the integration of libmsmcomm into FSO.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>